<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>a glitch in your system</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 17:04:26 +0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 17:04:26 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>1 Second Everyday - My Life at 25</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On my last birthday I decided to start a &lt;a href=&quot;http://1se.co/&quot;&gt;1 Second Everyday&lt;/a&gt; project - a video composed of 1 second videos taken every day for a year. This became some sort of a visual diary capturing random moments of my life at 25.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-app&quot;&gt;The app&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1SE application has a really nice interface and does what it is supposed to do - clip and store your videos on a timeline. It comes with nice additions like reminders and backup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: in the current version 2.5.4 for Android there is a problem with the clipping and compiling with some devices which can be fixed by turning off the &lt;strong&gt;Hardware compile&lt;/strong&gt; option in the Settings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big thanks to my SO who gave me interesting ideas, did the video compressing and added some cool music to the final video. Also, thanks to all of you who are in this video ^^&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/212460622&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/212460622&quot;&gt;1 Second Everyday - My Life at 25&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/user65236944&quot;&gt;M&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The video will be public for a few days only. If you want to see it after that, just ask :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 17:38:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//1-second-everyday-my-life-at-25.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//1-second-everyday-my-life-at-25.html</guid>
        
        <category>video</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reasons why I don't use Facebook </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a few years since I deactivated my Facebook account and I don’t regret it. People sometimes ask me why - well, I am neither asocial nor friendless. I am just one of &lt;em&gt;those people who don’t use Facebook&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/metadata.jpg&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-like-my-privacy&quot;&gt;I like my privacy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies like Facebook trick you into thinking that you’re the customer and in control of your data. Unfortunately, you are the &lt;strong&gt;product&lt;/strong&gt; and totally killing you privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Facebook’s business model is to be the man in the middle; to track every move you, your family, and your friends make, to store all that information indefinitely, and continuously analyse it to understand you better in order to exploit you by manipulating you for financial and political gain.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Aral Balkan, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ar.al/notes/encouraging-individual-sovereignty-and-a-healthy-commons/&quot;&gt;Encouraging individual sovereignty and a healthy commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook has made it harder for users to understand exactly what they’re giving away - third parties pay to access your interests, photos, likes, purchasing intensions and connections. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://veekaybee.github.io/facebook-is-collecting-this/&quot;&gt;data which is collected&lt;/a&gt; is more than you have imagined. Why should we let businesses privatize our social discourse?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-have-alternatives&quot;&gt;I have alternatives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not using Facebook doesn’t mean I cannot easily connect with people. I can always write an e-mail or make a phone call, I am also on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As social animals we can’t bear the idea of missing out and so many find themselves placing their most intimate expressions onto a businessman’s hard-disk, buried deep in a data center in another country - one they will never be allowed to visit.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cryptoparty.in/learn/handbook&quot;&gt;The CryptoParty Handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-dont-feel-lonely&quot;&gt;I don’t feel lonely&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friendships on Facebook are pasive and unhealthy compared with actual socialization. They even make us lonelier than before. I prefer investing my time in face-to-face meetings which make the whole interaction more personal and emotional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/70534716&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-need-to-disconnect&quot;&gt;I need to disconnect&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disconnecting means unplugging from the technologies we use and love. Always being connected can make us anxious or even addicted. Visiting a new place and/or staying offline helps me a lot when I’m feeling overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The ease of digital distraction has made us appreciate solitude with a new intensity. We savor being face-to-face with a small group of friends or family in one place and one time far more thanks to the digital sociality that so fluidly rearranges the rules of time and space.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thenewinquiry.com/essays/the-irl-fetish/&quot;&gt;The IRL fetish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-might-want-to-reinvent-myself&quot;&gt;I might want to reinvent myself&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not many people realize that anything posted online might come to haunt them permanently one day, yet everyone needs space to grow. I don’t want to document every aspect of my life, no matter good or bad, just to regret it a few years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What they don’t tell you is that it’s impossible to move, to live, to operate at any level without leaving traces, bits, seemingly meaningless fragments of personal information. Fragments that can be retrieved, amplified…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;William Gibson, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johnny_Mnemonic&quot;&gt;Johnny Mnemonic&lt;/a&gt; (1981)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-dont-want-to-waste-my-time&quot;&gt;I don’t want to waste my time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is limited and learning how to prioritize is important. I am trying to reduce the number of things that require my attention so that I can happily apply more attention to those things I care the most about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 23:38:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//reasons-why-i-dont-use-facebook.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//reasons-why-i-dont-use-facebook.html</guid>
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Desserts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Baking has been one of my hobbies for a few years. I am not sure when did it happen but I feel like I’ve always been interested in cooking. With the rise of the Internet, providing an endless resource of recipes next to my cookbooks, I started cooking different desserts and discovered I mostly enjoy baking muffins and cookies. I decided to upload the photos of my favourite desserts - if you’re curious about a recipe, just drop a comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; data-footer=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/147251133@N04/albums/72157679803118985&quot; title=&quot;Desserts&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/649/31789222394_56513576c6_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;Desserts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 21:09:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//desserts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//desserts.html</guid>
        
        <category>desserts</category>
        
        <category>hobbies</category>
        
        <category>photos</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>European Week for Waste Reduction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ewwr.eu/en&quot;&gt;The European Week for Waste Reduction&lt;/a&gt; takes place between the 19th and the 27th of November 2016 and is aiming to promote culture of sustainable use of resources and waste management. This year the focus is on &lt;strong&gt;packaging waste&lt;/strong&gt; and the ways to reduce it. The Bulgarian initiative &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sipieu.com/&quot;&gt;СИПИ.еу&lt;/a&gt; participates with the following &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/1695534674096707/&quot;&gt;challenge&lt;/a&gt; and the tag &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#СприИзползванетоНаПластмасаЗаЕднократнаУпотреба&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring your own cup instead of using a plastic one&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring a reusable cloth bag instead of buying a plastic one&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fill you own bottle and take it with you instead of buying drinks in plastic bottles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy in bulk instead of getting packaged products&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use your own containers while shopping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Zero Waste&lt;/strong&gt; lifestyle is becoming more and more popular these days. Despite the fact that this culture is still not very well-known in Bulgaria, it is possible (with some willingness and persistence) to reduce the waste you produce. Every day a huge ammount of plastic disposables are thrown away in nature and remain there. Forever. &lt;em&gt;Do you really want a big pile of plastic to be what’s left after you?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You cannot easily make people change their consumer habbits but you can give them a good example.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 09:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//european-week-for-waste-reduction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//european-week-for-waste-reduction.html</guid>
        
        <category>EWWR2016</category>
        
        <category>WasteReductionWeek</category>
        
        <category>zerowaste</category>
        
        <category>recycling</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It was high time I started &lt;a href=&quot;http://tom.preston-werner.com/2008/11/17/blogging-like-a-hacker.html&quot;&gt;blogging like a hacker&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, a static site generator in Ruby, was exactly what I needed. It converts raw text files in various formats and generates a complete, static website. All of the content is hosted and version-controlled on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mbdimitrova/mbdimitrova.github.io&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Basically, I write my posts in Markdown using my test editor of choice, VIm, then I commit and push to Github. Awesome, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ready, Set, Go!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 12:18:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//hello-world.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//hello-world.html</guid>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
